

Plön, Germany

"Plain practice is the bread of life."

I am a Computer Scientist with 6+ years of experience working as a programmer and R&D researcher in various state-of-art projects. This taught me how to be a quick learner, adaptable and self-driven. I am passionate trying out new solutions to problems and working in a team of curious people. My main interests are Computer Graphics (mainly rendering) and Computer Simulation.

## **Personal Projects & Skills**

**Personal Website** A personal website with links to my personal projects and experiments, built using Javascript (Three.js)

BioCrowds in Unity3D C#, Unity3D, Data oriented and parallelized simulation algorithms. **Deferred Renderer** C++, Vulkan, HLSL, GLSL, Rendering Algorithms and Data Structures

> Languages Portuguese (native speaker), English (C1), German (B1)

# **Experience**

**Freelance** Brazil -> Plön, Germany

• Relocation to Germany. (aprox. 9 months)

• German Studies. Acquired B1 Certificate. (aprox. 7 months)

- Tutoring Computer Graphics, Programming and Machine Learning. (aprox. 1 year)
- Studied Vulkan and modern Graphics APIs. (ongoing, aprox 6 months.)
- Studied CG on Web platforms (Javascript, Threejs) (aprox. 1 year)

Lenscope Remote, (São Paulo. Brazil)

COMPUTER VISION/GRAPHICS SPECIALIST

• R&D of Computer Vision and Graphics algorithms applied to the optometry business.

- · Worked directly with a PhD teammate, embedded into a larger AGILE team of 7 developers and 2 managers.
- Project in Python with Keras, Pandas and Numpy.

#### Virtual Humans Lab (PUCRS)

Porto Alegre, Brazil RESEARCHER Nov 2017 - Mar 2021

• Main project was BioClouds, a large crowd simulation model. Resulted in 5 published papers.

Mainly used C# in Unity3D. But we also had projects in C++ (for fluid simulation) and Python (for computer vision).

HP inc. R&D Porto Alegre, Brazil R&D INTERNSHIP 2016 - 2017

· Worked in a 6 member AGILE team. Composed of 4 interns, 1 machine learning specialist, and 1 manager.

- · Implemented the Computer Vision system that integrated a video camera with gesture commands
- Project in C++ with OpenCV, Java and Python.

#### LIS/HP inc. at FACIN (PUCRS)

Porto Alegre, Brazil R&D INTERNSHIP 2015 - 2016

• AGILE team of 3 interns and 1 technical lead. Built a tool in Python to label video datasets.

• Project in C++ and Python with OpenCV.

**NLP Lab (PUCRS)** Porto Alegre, Brazil

RESEARCH INTERNSHIP 2015 - 2016

- Participated in publishing SUMMIT++, an annotated corpus for the Portuguese language.
- Work in a team for 2 interns, 3 PhD candidates. Project in Java and Python.

### **Degrees**

## **MSc, Computer Science**

PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE DO SUL (PUCRS)

· Awarded a full ride merit scholarship.

## **BSc, Computer Science**

PONTIFICAL CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF RIO GRANDE DO SUL (PUCRS)

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Mar 2019 - Mar 2021

2022 - Current

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021

Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

2015 - 2018